When I first met Candy
当我初次遇见凯蒂
Those were like the days of juice..
时光如果汁般甜美
Everything was bountiful...
一切都变得丰富多彩
Birds filled the sky ...
鸟儿在天空翱翔
a great kindness float through us...
一股暖流在我们之间流淌
Heaven
天堂
Here it is.
给你
I'm gonna try it your way this time.
这次我用你的办法试试
This is just as good this way. Honestly.
坦白说 这办法不错
Then why don't you do it?
那你怎么还不动手
Schumann, Why don't I do it?
舒曼 为什么我不动手
Dan is a follower, Candy. Not a leader.
凯蒂 丹只是跟班 不是老大
We stick to snorting, keep it simple.
简单点儿 一直用鼻子吸
You know...Dare to be different!
有时候 你要敢于尝试不同!
Well I think I'd like to try it in the bath.
我认为我应该去浴盆试试
well that's different.
这就是不同
Candy?
凯蒂?
Candy!
凯蒂!
Schumann, fucking help me!
舒曼 快来帮我!
What?
怎么了?
Come here!
快来!
Come here!Babe?
快来! 宝贝?
Oh, Christ!
噢 天哪
Shit, I think that she took too much.
该死 她摄入过量了
Babe!
宝贝
Fucking saline solution or something? I need saline solution!
快给我些生理盐水或者别的什么东西 我需要生理盐水
What?
什么?
Fuck it!Go and get a glass of water...
我操! 赶紧拿杯水来!
Put salt in it! Hurry up!
放盐进去 快!
Come on!Babe!
醒醒 宝贝
Candy! Look at me!
凯蒂 看着我!
How much salt?
放多少盐?
I don't know! HEAPS!
我不知道! 看着放吧
Just fucking stir it! Make sure it's dissolved!
快他妈搅啊 确保充分溶解
Come here!Oh baby? Fuck!!
快来! 噢 宝贝! FUCK!
I don't think this works man!What the fuck's salt gonna do?
哥们儿 这有屁用! 盐能干啥!
Shut up!
闭嘴!
Fuck!Hold her arm!
操! 扶着她的胳膊
Hold her fucking arm, man!
你他妈扶着她的胳膊!
Harder!
用力!
This will not be ...
这不会...(管用的)
Here we go ...
开始吧
No, it's not gonna fucking work!It's bullshit!!
不 它完全不起作用 狗屎!
Shut up!
闭上你的乌鸦嘴
Call an ambulance.
叫救护车
Here we go.
我们走
Candy, look at me.
凯蒂 看着我
Candy! Candy!
凯蒂! 凯蒂!
Candy, Look at me!
凯蒂 看着我!
Babe ...
宝贝
Bring her back.
带她回来
...back.
...回来
Enough with the fucking salt.
我他妈已经放了不少盐了
It was beautiful.
感觉很美妙
Intense.
我有点紧张
The future or the thing that gleamed.
未来飘忽不定
The present was so very, very good.
当下如此美妙
I wasn't trying to wreck Candy's life
我从没想过毁去凯蒂的生命
I was trying to make mine better.
我努力使自己变得更好
We wanted to share absolutely everything.
我们渴望分享所有一切
Especially the best bits .
尤其是最好的
I want to stay with you forever.
我要永远和你在一起
...and who would'nt!
谁不想呢?
It's us!
画的是我俩!
It's called "The afternoon of extravagant delight. "
我称之为
By Candy Wyatt.
"狂欢的午后"
It's beautiful.
太美了
I love it!
我喜欢这种感觉
Casper.
卡斯珀
Casper, It's Dan.
卡斯珀 是丹啊
Daniel, hang on!, I'm coming in on a win and a prayer!
丹尼尔 等等 我即将带着胜利和祈祷而来
What?
什么?
I'm trying to land a Jumbo in Dubai.
我正试着在迪拜降落
Casper was like the dad you always wanted.
卡斯珀就像你一直想要的父亲
The one that lets you have lollies and fizzy drinks
他允许你吃糖果和冷饮
he lets you stay up late,
他允许你晚归
and watch movieslate at night.
允许你晚上一直看电影
Daniel, how are you?
丹尼尔 你好吗
Casper and I went way back.
卡斯珀和我是多年的朋友
I love you
我爱你(法语)
Is that right?
我说的对吗?
Yes!
是的
This is George.
这是乔治
A very limited English,but a very large penis.
罕见的英国人 本钱(指男性那话儿)雄厚
Isn't that right, George?
我说的没错吧 乔治
Ok.
你说是就是吧
Our entire conversation is based on the 1995 "Lonely Planet" guide to Havana
我们从Lonely Planet 95年出版的哈瓦那旅行指南说起
Sit down.
请坐
Just good friends.
都是好朋友嘛
So, what's on the agenda today?
今天有什么安排
Not much, we're just wandering around.
没啥 我们想四处逛逛
Um, Could you spare us $50?
嗯 能不能借给我们50块
Does is ever embarrassed you, Candy?...His naked desperation!
凯蒂 他赤裸裸的绝望让你难堪了吗
Nakedness, I can deal with!
裸体 我可以应付
Or give us some ecstasy .we can sell for it?
或者给我们一些迷幻药 我们可以拿去卖吗?
I'm afraid that my days as a manufacturer of ...
只怕我作为一名娱乐制药商的
recreational farmaceuticals has come to an end.
日子已经到头了
Why's that?
为什么呢?
I've been made Associate Professor of Organic Chemistry.
我现在是有机化学副教授了
- Wow! Congratulations. - Great.
- 哇呜! 恭喜你! - 太棒了!
So, suddenly I have a reputation to uphold.
因此 我要维护我的声誉
Well in that case, could we make it a hundred?
那么既然如此 100块可以不?
We'll pay it back!
我们会还你的!
Thanks, Cas.
谢了 卡斯珀
Everything's alright, isn't it?
你没事儿吧?
It's just a cash flow problem.Only 7 days.
只是现金周转问题 七天而已
And you, Candy?
你呢 凯蒂
Being one that's so new to the path of the dead!
这是条通向死亡的新路!
She is fine.
她很好
When you can stop,people don't want to...
当断不断
... and when you want to stop,You can't!
必受其乱
One of life's little riddles!
生命就像筛子
What Grandma?
省省吧 老太太
Off you go!
你们可以走了
Thank you, Casper.
谢谢你 卡斯珀
Okay, are you ready?
你好了吗?
One, two, three ...
一 二 三...
I feel like some confused Sesame Street character!
我像《芝麻街》里的角色一样困惑
Start the car.
开车
My own parents had long since cut me adrift
我父母很久以前就对我放任自流了
The Wyatts, on the other hand,kept their firm hold on the ropes.
凯蒂的父母 相反地 管教很严
Do you want more potatoes?
还要土豆吗?
It was nice to visit places where the fridge was always full.
我喜欢来这儿 就是为了大饱口福
I shall have to bring my plate round when I come here!
下次来这儿我要带上盘子
I think you'll find that's part of the carbohydrate.
我想你会发现那是部分碳水化合物
What do you think?
你有主意没?
I don't know.I don't know.
我不知道 我不知道
See how you go.
看你怎么做了
Stretchers?
担架?
They're like wooden frames you stretch the canvass on.
就是在木架子上铺上帆布
and anyway, I feel really stupid ...
不管怎样 我觉得很蠢
I did about a month ago,and as of tomorrow I'm gonna lose our deposit on the stretchers.
我大约一个月前做的 我把我们的存款都搭在担架上了
It is really rude to ask ...
恕我冒昧地问一句
but at least I won't surprise her!
至少我不想令她感到惊讶
I can give you the money back the next time I see you again.
下次见你我会还钱
Can you ring him, and tell him to wait for a week?
你能给他打电话 让他等一个星期吗
I already tried that pretty much last week.
上星期我已经很努力地尝试过了
What if I rang him for you?
我给他打电话怎样?
I haven't got the card with me.
我没带卡
How much is it?
多少钱
150.
150块
Mate, the question is not the money.
不是钱的问题
I really appreciate it.
我非常感激
The question...is the future of my daughter.
问题是...我女儿的将来
Mate, she's fantastic!
她简直妙极了
Should see her paintings!
你该看看她的画作
The question is you.
问题出在你身上
When are you gonna do something?
你打算何时有所作为
I've got some ideas.
我已经有了主意
I've sent some of my poems into Heat magazine.
我给一些热门杂志寄去了我的诗作
- Here we are! - Milk...and sugar, There!
- 咖啡来了! - 牛奶...糖 在那儿!
- Thanks babe! - Thanks, Elaine.
- 谢谢你 甜心 - 谢谢你 伊莱恩
You're not a teenager anymore.
你不再是小孩了
You know that, don't you?
你知道这回事 不是吗
Yes, I know that, Jim.
是的 我知道 吉姆
that is why I did'nt want you to do it!
所以我不想你做这事儿
No, it's alright! It's fine!
别啊 它很好 很棒
Look at it!You've turned it into butter!
你瞅瞅!你把它全弄进奶油里去了!
I told you to keep it on blend!
我告诉过你用混的
I put it on "Whip", because I'm whipping cream!
我用的是搅 因为我在搅奶油
Yes, but you don't know how to use it.
但是你一窍不通
Right... You do it!!
好吧 你来弄
- Uhh! Well it's too late now! - Ah well! Excuse me!!
- 呜! 已经太迟了! - 啊! 很抱歉!
Well all these settings are relative,and if you're not familiar with the workings of the machine ...
所有设置都是相关的 如果你不熟悉它的操作...
Then why the fuck does it say "Whip"?
那这儿为啥写着"搅拌"
I'll give them ice cream.
我要给他们做冰激凌
And please don't swear.
别骂骂咧咧的
Right! Well, I was going to give you cream,but I'm going to have to give you Ice Cream.
好吧! 我本打算给你们做冰激凌 现在只能给你们奶油了
-  Everything okay in there? - Well, we live in hope!
- 一切都顺利吗?  - 我们活在希望之中
A good place to live.
这是个好居所
Go!!
去吧!!
I wonder if that was it?
我不知道这是否?
If that was what?
是否什么?
The last shot.
我们的弹药(指毒品)耗尽了
I wouldn't care.
我不在乎
It was my Nana's.
这是祖母留下的
We're going to sell anything.We're only hocking it!
我们不会卖任何东西 我们只是将它典当出去
We'll get it back!
会赎回来的
$25.
25块
and He doesn't want the paints.
他不想要这些画
I'll be back!
我会回来的
He said maybe we could work something out!.
他说也许我们应该另想办法
Let's go!
开车
Yes, I fucked him!
是的 我跟他上床了
For $50.
为了50块
I stink!
我真贱!
You okay?
你没问题吧?
I'm Sorry.
我很抱歉
Don't be!
别这样!
Here is the deepest secret that nobody knows .
这是一个无人知晓的深藏已久的秘密
Here is the root of the root,and the bud of the bud...
这颗生命之树 它是根之根 是芽之芽
and the sky of the sky,in the tree called life .
是天空的天空
which grows higher than soul can hope, or mind can hide .
它高过灵魂之期盼 不能被思想隐藏
and this is the one that is keeping the stars apart.
它是让繁星保持距离的奇迹
I carry your heart.
我把你的心带在身上
I carry it in my heart.
用我的心将它妥善保藏
Will you marry me?
你会嫁给我吗
We will be man and wife.
我们会成为夫妻
One flesh.
共结连理
I will ask them if they freely undertake the obligations of marriage ...
你们是否自愿承当婚姻的责任
... and to state that there is no legal impediment to the marriage.
并且确定没有法律障碍
Are you ready,freely and without reservation ...
你们准备好了吗 完全自愿并且没有任何异议地...
to give yourself to eachother... in marriage?
把自己献给对方而成就一段美满姻缘
We are!
是的 我们准备好了
Are you ready for love and honor each other ...
你们是否愿意互相敬爱 彼此忠诚
as husband and wife, for the rest of your life?
相敬如宾 共度余生
- We are! - We are!
我们愿意!
Candice and Dan ...
凯蒂 丹尼尔
Come back, love.
回来 亲爱的
Ah, okay.
啊 好的
Alright everyone, Close together! Balloons down, Jenny.
大家靠近一点 珍妮 气球往下一点
Big smiles, everyone! Happy Day!
大家笑一笑! 大喜的日子!
One, two... Oh, Shit!
一 二...哇靠
Schumann!
舒曼!
- One, two... Three! - Right...
- 一 二...三! - 好...
Alright everyone! Back to our place for a few drinks,and a bite to eat?
大家不去吃点儿喝点儿?
I'm sorry, I'm going to have to go,I've got an appointment!
很抱歉 我必须走了 我有个约会
Oh! Well, I hope that nobody else has got an appointment!
哦 好吧 希望其他人没有约会
I'm in for the long hall, Mrs. Wyatt.
怀亚特夫人 我可是期待很久了
Good.
很好
No, I hate spelling!
不 我恨拼写
Yeah, me too! Spelling and maths!
我也是! 最恨拼写和数学!
I was always hopeless at spelling and maths.
我一直对拼写和数学深恶痛绝
- I like English. - English?
- 我喜欢英文 - 英文?
Like stories and stuff?
就像故事之类?
Yeah!
嗯
English and Sport!
英文和体育!
Well you can't go wrong there.
那你可不能行差踏错
You can be a Sports journalist.
你可以做体育记者
Really?
真的吗
I could see you as a sports journalist.
我一看你就是当体育记者的料
Well, Dan, you're laughing mate!
好嘛 丹尼尔 你真可笑
Financing this love as a married couple.
帮帮这对小夫妻吧
You get the first one under your belt,you pour everything into it.
你已经得到了你最想要的 你为它付出了你的一切
After that, the minimum equity is what you're after.
毕竟 你要的并没有低于你的最低期望
You get into as much debt as possible.
你现在负债累累
It gives you some focus.
婚姻可使你更专注一些
I'm not just talking about real estate.
我不仅仅在说不动产
I'm talking about a philosophy.
我还在跟你讨论生活的哲学
Would you mind...if you excuse me for a minute?
不好意思 打扰一下
No! Sure!!
请便!
Where are you and Dan going for the honeymoon?
你和丹去打算哪儿度蜜月?
-  More lemonade?  - Yeah, thanks!
- 需要柠檬水吗? - 谢谢!
You're so tight! You're selling next year?
你太紧张了! 明年升中学了吗?
Abbots Road! It's just round the corner from us!
阿波茨路! 就在我们附近!
Geez, that'll be a change, eh?
天哪 那会有所不同的 嗯?
Yeah, I'd rather go to a state school,but, it's mom and dad...
耶 我想读州立学校 但是我父母...
Jenny, could you come and help with sanwiches
珍妮 过来帮我弄三明治
I'll give you a hand too, Auntie Cap!
我也来帮手 凯珀阿姨
-  What? -  What are you doing in there?
- 咋了? - 你们在那儿干嘛?
Doing a shit.
没干什么
No you're not!
你小子有鬼!
Open the door.
开门
I can't!
不行!
You greedy fuckup!!
你这贪婪的杂碎
Rather a selfish way to begin a marriage!
结婚是个相当自私的选择
Really! All done!
真的! 全完了!
Dick!
蠢货!
Obviously, it was a big dope weekend!
显然 这是属于瘾君子的周末!
You wanna be relaxed at your own wedding.
谁不想在自己的婚礼上放松
- Sorry about that. - That's fine!
- 对此我很抱歉 - 这没什么
So where were we?
我们说到哪儿了?
I was saying, you need to get your t...
我说了 你应该尝试...
Do you need a seat? Yeah, sure! Have a seat!
你不坐吗? 请坐吧!
You need to get your toe in the the market, Jim!
吉姆 你该了解市场
You know what I'mn saying? Out of suburbs, fine!
你明白我的意思吗? 住到远郊 很好!
Two bedroom...
两间卧房...
...You don't need a garden courtyard, do you?
你们不需要带花园庭院吗?
You want the worst house, in the best street!
你竟然在最棒的街区住最差的房子!
You don't need a kitchen or bathroom...
你们需要厨房或者浴室吧...
Put it in later!
再说吧!
Say for example, you want to borrow ...
比方说 你要借...
400.
400块
Or 300
或者300
You do it...You Struggle...
你想借钱...你内心争斗...
Understand?
你的明白?
Dan?
丹?
Dan!
丹!
Dan...
丹...
Wake up.
醒醒
Dan, Dan, wake up.
丹 丹 醒醒
I'm fucked.
我惨了
Too much champagne.
他喝了太多的香槟
Yeah I'm...I'm sure it's that...
我...我可以肯定
Well, it is the big day!
这是个大日子
I'll make some coffee.
我煮点儿咖啡
He's drunk!
他醉了!
Is there anything you want to talk to me about?
你想和我谈些什么吗?
What?
什么?
What's going on?
发生什么事了?
Mum, you know what's going on!
妈 你知道的!
We are having a lovely time!
我们要享受一段美好时光
That's not what I meant.
我不是那个意思
Well then, I don't know what you mean!
那么 我就不知道你什么意思了
What's wrong with Dan?
丹咋了?
He's just pissed, Mum!He's hopeless!!
他醉了 妈妈 他没什么
Sorry.
对不起
Thanks for the beautiful reception.
谢谢你们的盛情款待
It'd kill your father, you know.
你要知道 那会气死你父亲的
Think we should stop?
你不认为我们应该戒掉吗
- What? Now that we're respectable? - Yeah, I know!
- 什么? 难道我们不够体面吗? - 是的 很体面!
You know what I mean.
你知道我的意思
Whenever you say the word.
任何时候你说的"戒"这个词 我都明白
We are the coolest people in McDonalds!
我们是麦当劳里最酷的人
We had a lot going for us.
我们有很多优点
We'd found the secret glue that held all things together
我们发现了将一切聚合起来的秘诀
in a perfect place...
在一个没有噪音的
...where the noise did not intrude.
完美之地
Our world was...so very complete.
我们的世界是如此...完整
Earth
大地
- Hey baby! - Hi!
- 嘿 宝贝! - 嗨!
How was it?
它怎么样?
About the same.
都差不多
Here's $200.
给你200块
I'm gonna give it half an hour and then I'll split!
我大概需要半个钟头
Yeah. I won't be long.I'll meet you at home.
耶 我不会太久 家里见
Ok, I see you there.
好的 家里见
OK.
好的
They say that for every 10 years you've been a junkie ...
有人说 用不了十年你就会成为一名吸毒者
You will have spent 7 of them...waiting.
你会花七年等待
One way is not bad have as much time to think .
一边花同样的时间思考
on the other, the anxiety was a full time job!
一边忍受着工作的苦闷
-  Hey? -  You slimey cunt!
- 嘿? - 你这个贱人!
-  What?  -  What do you fucking reckon?
- 咋了? - 你他妈怎么看这事儿?
I just had a quick little bit! It was nothing!
我只是稍微快了点儿 啥也没有
Where?
哪里?
Um, In the park. When I met Ange.
唔 公园 我遇见安吉的时候
Did Angela do it with you?
安吉拉和你一起那啥了?
No, of course not! We left as soon as we did the deal!
没 当然没 我们交易完就离开了
Only because he's decent enough to go home to his girlfriend.Like you should be!
他可以体面地回家见他女友 你本来也可以!
Oh candy! He sold me the dope! Why would he want to have a hit in the public toilet?
哦 凯蒂! 他卖我大麻! 为啥他总想着在公共厕所里备受欢迎?
Well why the fuck would you?
那你他妈也这么想?
Oww!Look, I admit it was dumb!
哇呜! 听着 我承认这很蠢!
Okay?
你满意了?
I'm Sorry!
我很遗憾!
Will you let me make you a nice taste!
让我给你尝点儿甜头吧!
I'm getting sick of this, dickhead!
白痴 我讨厌这样!
What is your problem?
你的问题出在哪儿?
You are my problem!
你就是我的问题!
You are a waste of space.
你的存在简直是在浪费空间
Are you getting your period or something?
你找到了自己的人生或其他什么吗?
No, Dan.
没有 丹!
I hardly have my period anymore!
我再也没有自己的人生了!
...because my body's all fucked up!
因为我的身体已经沉沦了!
It's this fucking nightmare you've led me into!
是你把我带进这个该死的梦靥
Oh right! Like I held a gun to your head! Did I? Eh??
哦 是吗? 我有拿枪指着你的头让你吸毒吗?
Held you down, hit you up, did I?
我有逼你这么做吗?
Fuck You!
操你大爷!
Fuck you too, Candy!
操你妈的 凯蒂!
Well, Fuck you double then!
那好 我操你全家!
Dan, have you noticed, the more I work, the less I paint?
丹 你发现没有 我越认真 画得越差
Candy, I don't want a fight! OK?
凯蒂 我不想争吵!
I just don't see what your problem is tonight! I mean...
我就是不明白今晚你是怎么了! 我是说...
We've got a life!
我们一起生活!
It's neither good nor bad! OK?
这没有什么好坏之分!
Do you know... Do you know what I do?
你知道...你知道我在做什么吗?
Listen to this, dick fuck!
仔细听着 蠢货!
What do I do all day?
我整天都在干嘛?
I fuck men I hate!
我恨我现在的境况!
- Don't do this. - What are going to do about it?
- 别这样  - 我该怎么办?
Look, Okay, that's it! Alright?
看这 就靠这个! 不是吗?
No more brothels, No more escorts!
没有妓院 没有陪伴!
- We're gonna take the time to start a new life! - You don't understand do you?
- 我们正开始崭新的生活!  - 你根本不懂
That's really it this time.That's going away!
这就是我们的新生活 过去的让它过去吧
Maybe I want to keep using!
或许我想继续
You know, I'm sick of working,yes,but...
你知道 我讨厌工作 是的 但是
...What if I want to keep using? What are you gonna do about it?
假如我要继续吸毒 你会怎么办?
Candy!
凯蒂!
Why don't you ring gay blokes?
你怎么不去找个同性恋
You start working!You hock your ass!
你开始工作! 你去卖自己的屁股!
Hey, you know you can not do that!
嘿 你不可以这么做
You know, I'll get...I'll get AIDS!
你想想 我会...我会得艾滋!
No you won't, you moron!
你不会 白痴!
You'll make them use condoms,like everybody else!
你可以跟所有人一样用避孕套
I wouldn't know what to do.
我不知道怎么办
You're heterosexual, right? So you're just doing what you're good at anyway.
你是异性恋 对吧? 你只要做你擅长的事情就行了
Did you even hear what you're saying?
你知道自己在说什么吗?
Let me fuck women, no problems!
让我去干女人 没问题!
If I can do it with women, I'd make us all the money! You'd never have to work, I swear!
如果我干女人可以来钱 我保证你不用工作
But... These women, they want muscle types, don't they?
但是...这些女人不是喜欢肌肉男吗?
If there was a market out there, I'd do it, but I don't think there is!
如果做鸭有市场 我乐意做 但是我不认为有市场
And I'd be hopeless with the gay stuff! You know that!
而且你要知道 我不可能成为同性恋
You're fucking unbeleivable!
你他妈的真令人难以置信
I can't get to sleep with that on.
开着电视我睡不着
Can you turn it off?
你能关了它吗?
Candy, it's a really good movie!
凯蒂 这的确是部优秀的影片
I'll turn it down, okay?
我把声音调小一点 可以吗?
Anyway, it finishes in half an hour.
不管怎样 半小时就结束了
Fuck you!
去你妈的!
Go to bed.
上床!
How can you even hear that?
听到没有?
The light's bugging me!
光线干扰到我了!
I can't believe it.
我无法相信
I can't fucking believe it.
我真他妈难以相信
What? I'm not making any noise.
有怎么了? 我没发出任何动静
The light!
是光!
The Light's keeping me awake.
有光我睡不着!
OK, look! I'll cover the light!Hmm??
好吧 我把光遮起来 行了吗?
There's more light coming from the workshop than that!
这样光线就没那么强了!
Asshole!
混蛋!
The pen!! I can hear the pen scratching on the paper!
笔! 我听见笔划过纸的声音!
How? This is ridiculous, Candy.
这太荒谬了 凯蒂!
You're just looking for an excuse!
你在找借口!
Turn off the light and come to bed.
关灯上床!
I'm not going to discuss this with you anymore!
我不想再和你讨论这件事
Turn the light off!
关灯!
Nope! I'm not even talking to you!
不! 我也不想跟你说!
- Turn the fucking light off!! - ...Aghhh!
- 关上这该死的灯 - 啊哈!
Fuck!!
我操!
Oh my God! Oh my God!
哦 我天! 哦 我的天哪!
- Shit. - I'm so sorry, Danny!
- 靠!  - 对不起 丹尼!
- What the fuck was that? - Oh my God! Oh baby! Oh shit!
- 什么东西? - 哦 我的天! 哦 宝贝! 哦 糟糕!
Jesus! It's fuckin' blood!
天哪 流血了!
I didn't mean to hurt you...
我不是故意伤到你的...
Jesus fuckin' shit, alright!.Fuck!
西瓜 香蕉 你的大巴拉!
Is there any chance for some morphine?
可以用吗啡吗?
I'm in a fair bit of pain.
我很疼
I don't think you need any morphine.
我不觉得你需要吗啡
I don't think you're in much pain at all!
我觉得你不太疼
Oh well, it was worth a try!
值得一试啊!
Excuse me, would you mind if we um,bought a couple of flavoured milks off you?
打扰了 你不介意我们拿两瓶牛奶吧?
- Just take a couple. - You sure?
- 拿去吧 - 你确定?
No worries!
别担心!
- Want some of this? - Yeah!
- 要点这个? - 是的
- Have a good night! - Thanks. - Thankyou!
- 祝你过个愉快的夜晚! - 谢谢 - 谢谢你
D'you want anymore?
还要吗?
It's been a while.
有一阵没那个了
Yeah! It's been a while.
是啊 有一阵了
I'm sorry I hurt your head.
伤到你的头 我真的很内疚
I'll get you back!
我会让你好好起来的
Hello.... Anybody home?
喂 有人在家吗?
Who the fuck are you?
你他妈是谁?
Yeah, it's me! Phil.
是我 菲尔
Phillip Dudley,from Commercial Realty.
菲利普达德利 商业不动产经济
I've written to you lately.
我之前给你们寄过信
- What's the problem? - Well...
- 有什么问题吗? - 这个...
We've been writing to you about...Um...
我们是想通知你们 嗯...
I've got these..er.. hang on..Er, here they are!
我把信..呃..放在..呃..这儿
Copies of the three letters we've sent you recently...
三封信件的复印件 我们最近寄给你的...
Relating to the matter of your er,rent in arrears.
关于...呃...你们欠下的租金
I'm here to confirm that the 3rd of these letters is in actual fact a notice to vacate.
我过来确认一下 第三封信是通知你们搬出
Effective 7 days hence.
在七天之内
Fuck!
我靠!
Well of course it was...28 days when you received the letter.
事实上你们收到信已经28天了
Now, what I'm actually here for today...
现在 我今天来此的初衷...
is to point out to you the shortfall owing on the fault of your bond.
是要指明你们的透支情况
Assuming... you've paid no more rent between now and next wednesday...
假如..你们直到下周三还不能交租
We've calculated that the shortfall will be er... $1,125.
我们算过 届时你们将透支..呃..1125元
Listen, Phillip...
听着 菲利普...
...we're junkies!
...我俩都吸毒!
I am a hooker!
我是个娼妓!
He's hopeless!
他游手好闲!
Right now, things are very complicated! We haven't got any money.
这样一来 事情好像变得复杂了 我们一分钱也没有
Right.
是的
But it was good...
但是这很好
Right when times got tough...
当日子变得艰难
There was always Casper. .
还有卡斯珀帮我们
Ah, the young ones!
啊 年轻人
Hi!
嗨!
Our... port in the storm!
他就是我们暴风雨中的港湾
Don't get overexcited!
别疯过头了!
our gingerbread house!
是为我们遮风挡雨的房子
For once... Here I come...Bearing Treats!
就一次...我来这儿...给你们好东西
So is this it?
就是它了?
An honour student didn't show, so I had an idle hour to fill.
不是我自夸 我花了一个小时来配药
You made that in an hour?
你做这个用了一个小时
Well... Panadine to morphine,in about an hour and 10!
帕纳丁(一种镇痛药)加吗啡 花了我一小时十分钟
If you get rid of the paracetamol...
如果你有扑热息痛
...do a few things...
你知道怎么做
...and morphine to heroin in 15 minutes.
15分钟之内连同吗啡一起加进海洛因
Thankyou, you guys!
谢谢 伙计们
Rearrange the atoms...
重新排列
...take a bit off...
取出一点
...put a bit on...
放进一点
Liquid Diamorphine...
二乙酰吗啡
Commonly known as heroin,pharmaceutical grade, pure.
一般被称为海洛因 专业制药级别的 高纯度
I call it "My Yellow Jesus!"
我称之为"疯狂耶稣"
Papa bear.
熊爸爸
Mama bear.
熊妈妈
Baby bear.
熊宝宝
It's just that... Candy says I have to start pulling my weight!
凯蒂说我必须开始尽一份力
Yeah.
耶
What do you know about gay escorts?
你了解同性伴侣吗
Growth market.
同性恋越来越多
Would you mind if asked you a few technical questions?
介意我问一些技术上的问题吗?
There's nothing I'd rather discuss with you!
我没什么想跟你说的!
What do they expect you to do?
他们希望你做什么?
Well there's a big down in the park!
公园里有一大堆同性恋!
Why don't you pop down and do some research!
你为什么不去研究研究!
I mean...
我是说...
If they pay you, would they expect you to have a stiffie?
如果他们给你钱 他们希望你的阴茎勃起吗?
It Helps!
勃起的阴茎会有用的
I don't think I could manage that.
我不认为我能那样做
I'm just washing my hands.
我只是洗洗手而已
Alright!
那好吧!
He'll cancel his cards.
他会注销他的卡
Not if I get to him first.
如果我先遇到他,事情就不会像现在这样了.
M. Ro. Roger. Rog. Rogie baby!Roger, Donald.
罗..罗杰..罗基宝贝! 罗杰唐纳德
R.D. Here it is!
罗杰唐纳德 在这儿!
R.D. Moylan 48 Charles Street, Petersham.
罗杰唐纳德莫伊兰 彼得森区查尔斯街48号
He'll trace the call.
他会跟踪电话
That's why they invented prepaid phones.
这就是发明预付电话的原因
Ah, Hi! Roger?
啊 嗨 罗杰?
Is that Roger Moylan?
是罗杰莫伊兰吗?
Yeah, Look! Look, This is hard...
看 看 这很难...
I'm the guy who stole your wallet.
是我偷了你的钱包
Yep! No, hold on! I'm sorry, okay? That's why I'm calling! I'm really sorry!
不 别挂! 我说对不起 行了吧? 我打电话就是为了道歉 我真的很抱歉!
I just... I was after some money,I saw some cash... and you had none...
我只是...欠了一些债 我想要一些现金...而且你啥也没有...
I want to give your wallet back!
我想还您钱包!
No, I know! I feel so stupid!It's just that I'm...
是的 我知道 我很蠢! 我只是 只是...
I'm so lonely right now...
感到非常孤寂...
I've got no money,I've just come from Adelaide...
我没有钱 我来自阿德莱德(澳大利亚南部城市)
And I've got no friends...
我没有朋友...
You know, I saw the wallet on the seat,and I took it! I wasn't thinking!
我看见钱包在座位上 我就拿了 我想都没想!
And I'm not interested in your credit cards.
我对你的信用卡没有任何兴趣
I just want to do the right thing and give it back to you.
我只是想做对的事 把钱包还给你
Uhh...  Well, no! I mean now's not a good time, I...
啊...那好 不! 现在还不是时候 我...
I'm a little bit nervous about this whole thing anyway!
我对整件事有点儿紧张
Can we just...Let's meet in the morning!
我们可以...明天早上再碰面吗
What...What time do you go to work?
你几点...几点上班?
So you're in Petersham, right?
你住在彼得森 对吗?
Umm... Isn't there a footie oval down there or something?
嗯...那下面有个椭圆形的足球或者别的什么?
How about we meet out in front of the greyhound stand?
我们用最简单有效方式见面吧
9:30? Is that good?
九点半可以吗?
Well I'll be wearing a blue baseball cap!
那好 我到时会戴蓝色的棒球帽
Look! look, Take my number!
注意! 听着 这是我的号码!
You got a pen? Yep, Right...
你有笔吗? 好的...
- 0422 844 881 - [That's my Plumber's!]
- 0422 844 881 - [这是我家管道工的号码! ]
Yes, 881.
是的 881
Well, have you got...a mobile just in case there's a...
好吧 你有移动电话吧 万一...
Yeah... Yeah! Hey, Tell me one thing...
是的...是的...嘿 告诉我一件事...
How did you manage to get such a cute photo on your license?
你是的证件照怎么这么可爱?
I'm Sorry! Yeah, I'm sorry, I go too far!
很抱歉! 非常抱歉 我扯太远了!
Alright! 9:30 then! I'll see you then!
好吧 9点半 到时候见
Alright, Thanks Rog! Okay, bye!
很好 谢谢你 罗杰 再见
Imagine if you'd turned your powers to the benefit of mankind... Dan!
丹 想象一下为了人类的福祉而运用你的力量
Does this look like me?
这看起来像我吗?
Not even remotely.
一点儿也不
I could use these!
我可以借用一下你的眼镜!
And a bit of...
有点像...
...How about now?
现在如何?
Caucasian man with glasses.
戴眼镜的白种人
Yes!
棒极了
I felt like Tarzan,at fuckin' last!
我觉得自己像人猿泰山
I had to hunt down some food for Jane.
我得去为"简"(指凯蒂)猎取食物了
I knew it was in my power to do something brave.
我知道我该胆大妄为一回了
Yeah...
是的...
Can we talk about this when you get back to the office?
你回办公室后 我们可以谈谈吗?
20 minutes... Okay, bye!
20分钟之后...好的 再见!
Sorry about that!
很抱歉!
Good morning,How are you?
早上好 你好吗?
Ah, good!How are you?
很好 你好吗?
Good.
还好
I just uh, wanted to check my current balance on this please!
我是想核对一下余额
Okay, I'll just need to get you to enter in your PIN...
好的 输一下你的个人识别号
Oh God, I'm...terrible with this!
哦 天哪 我..感觉糟透了
God! Do you ever have trouble remembering your PIN?
天哪! 你有过记不住个人识别号的困扰吗?
You'd be surprised at the number of people who forget them.
对于记不住数字的人你确实该感到惊讶
Yeah I know! That's why I came inside...
我知道 所以我进来...
Because I couldn't remember it out at the ATM, and I thought...
我在ATM机外面记不住密码 我想...
You know I could just er..If I had ID?
如果我有身份证 我可以 呃...
No! I'm sorry, you need your PIN number for all transactions. It's...
不! 很抱歉 你需要个人识别号来交易
It's one of those security things!
这是安全保障之一
No! Of course, of course!I understand. Um...
是的 当然 当然 我理解
So you can't just...
你不能通融一下..
I really can't!
我真的不能!
Hello?
喂?
- Mr. Moylan? - Yes?
- 莫伊兰先生吗?  - 你是?
- Mr. Roger Moylan?  - Yes?
- 罗杰莫伊兰先生吗?  - 怎么?
Roger Moylan, This is Ewan Douglasfrom the Commonwealth Bank Security division...
罗杰莫伊兰 我是联邦银行安全部门的伊万道格拉斯
Yes? Is something the matter?
是的 有事吗?
We've been tracking some unusual activity on your credit card, in the last 24 hours...
在过去的24小时我们留意到您信用卡的一些非正常的交易
Oh no!
哦 不!
When was the last time you used your Master Card?
您最后一次使用主卡是在什么时候?
Um, look! I think my wallet was stolen last night...
听着! 我的钱包昨晚被偷了...
Did you report it missing?
您报失了吗?
I was just calling now!
我正在打电话报失!
But I called you.
但这是我给您打的电话
Um, I mean I was about to call.
我是说我正要给你们打电话
Sir, Mr. Moylan, I'm going to have to verify your details for a security check.
莫伊兰先生 我要核对一下您的详细信息
Would you please tell me your Date of Birth?
可以告诉我您的出生日期吗?
Um... 13th of March, 1977.
嗯...1977年3月13号
Mother's Maiden Name?
您母亲的姓氏是?
Er, Lynch.
呃 林奇
Number of security?
您的安全号码?
Is that like your PIN number?
是个人识别号吗?
Well, it shouldn't be...but you often find that it is!
不一定...但一般都是!
Umm...Try... 3279
嗯...试试3279
It's just one of those days, you know...where everythings just gone!
某些日子 你会忘记所有的事情
It happens all the time!
常有的事!
Um, but listen... I've already got my daily limit out from the ATM outside...
嗯 听着...我已经取到每日限额
...But I actually need more, because I'm trying to buy this beautiful old Mercedes....
但是我需要更多 我想买下一辆老式的梅赛德斯
...you know, the cream ones,you know, the TLS?
奶油色的 你知道的 TLS?
Anyway, the guy's willing to negotiate for cash...
话说回来 那些人总是要收现金
...$2247.
2247块
God, we're going to be in the poor house!
天哪 我们成穷光蛋了
...and 50 cents.
50分!
Never get sentimental about a car!
千万别对一辆车动感情!
I might just get you to check the available credit on this card...
我本来要你查一下这张卡的可用额度...
I can get a cash advance, can't I?
我可以取现吗?
Candy? Candy!
凯蒂? 凯蒂!
I did it! I did it! I fucking did it, baby!
我做到了 我他妈做到了 宝贝!
I fucking did it!
我他妈真的做到了!
God, You... are going to fucking LOVE me for this...
天 你会为此爱死我的!
7 Grand!!
7千块!
Oh god! You should have seen it! I was fucking great! It was like...
天! 你该看看它! 我太伟大了 它就像...
It was like that movie we saw with that...
就像那部电影
God, what was his name,that actor we like?
天 他叫啥来着 那个我们喜欢的演员?
...and he gets all that money,and he walks in and he's all coool,and stuf like that...
他得到了所有的钱 他简直酷毙了
Danny!
丹尼!
I'm pregnant.
我怀孕了
Shit.
糟糕
Candy.
凯蒂
Crap.
垃圾
It couldn't be, uh...
这不可能..呃..
No.
不
We never broke a condom.
我们从没弄破安全套啊!
I'd know.
我早就知道
It was the night I broke your skull.
是我弄伤你头的那晚
How fucking weird.
太疯狂了
One night.
一晚就怀上了
I can get an abortion.
我可以去做人流
No.
不行
No, no way!
不 不行!
This is good.
可以的
It was meant to be.
这是注定的
This is what we need.
这正是我们需要的
We've got to stop using.
我们必须戒毒了
Yeah.
是的
Yeah, of course.
是的 当然
Sugar?
要糖吗?
Two, please.
两勺
We've got some news everybody...
我们要告诉所有人
We're having a baby.
我们有孩子了
Ah, Darling!
啊 亲爱的
Candice, Good God.
凯蒂甜心 太棒了
We just wanted you to know that we've made some decisions. and uh...
我们必须明确一些事情
We've been putting some money aside,haven't we?
我们预留一部分钱出来养孩子
We're going to get out of that whole warehouse environment.
我们要离开这个"仓库"
...and live in a proper house.
住进更适合居住的房子
Yeah! We really want to raise our child in the....
是的 我们要在一个真正的"家"中
...in a proper home.
...将孩子养大
Have you told your parents?
你告诉你的父母了吗?
No.
没有
Day 1
第一天
We knew what we had to do.
我们知道我们要做什么
It takes alot of planning to stop.
有很多计划搁浅
Lucky at last!We can really do this, Candy.
上天保佑! 我们一定可以做到 凯蒂!
It's going to be hard, but...
虽然会很艰难 但是...
I'm sure it's like a bridge...
就像一座桥
And once we cross it,everything will be okay.
只要我们走过它 一切都会好起来
You can get back into your painting again...
你可以继续画画了...
Maybe we'll move to the country...
也许我们该搬到乡下去...
Grow some veggies...
种一点蔬菜...
Feed the chickens...
养几只鸡...
We could go live in Thailand...
我们应该搬到泰国...
Thailand would be great,if we didn't use.
泰国很好 只要我们不吸毒的话
Or the Himalayas.
或者去喜马拉雅山
We'll go canoeing...
我们将坐上独木舟
A bit of white water rafting...
在白色的浪花上漂流
Get healthy, sleep well...
积极健康 甜美入睡
...not have drugs in our system.
不用再受毒品的控制
How good would that be?
那样该有多好?
We really have to do this.
我们必须戒毒
We have to do it this time.
我们这次一定要做到
Yeah, we will.
是的 我们会的
We are.
我们
We're really fuckin' doing it!
我们正在努力
Day 2
第二天
Day 4
第四天
I can't do it.
我受不了了
Hey!Come back to bed.
嘿! 回床上来!
Alright? You'll catch a cold.
你会着凉的
Casper, It's Candy.
卡斯珀 是我 凯蒂
Ring me as soon as you get this.
你拿到货马上给我电话
We've tried your mobile.
我们打过你手机
I know we said to ignore us while we did this, but...
我知道我说过一旦我们要货你就不理我们但是...
3 days...
三天了...
...we did pretty well, but we're not feeling so great now.
...我们已经很出色了 但是我们现在感觉不是很好
We don't want you to ignore us now.
我们现在很需要你
Are you there?
你在吗?
Pick up if you're there.
在就说话
Pick up!
说话呀!
Okay, you're not there.
好吧 你不在
Call us!!
给我们电话
Shit! Shit!
妈的! 妈的!
Kojak? It's Candy!
科杰克吗? 我是凯蒂啊!
Um... Shit, not so good.
嗯...妈的 很不好
I'm really sick. I mean...
我很痛苦 我的意思是
We just need credit.
我们需要信誉
Uh... I can work a shift,and then I can pay you back.
呃...我会去工作 之后我会还钱的
Yeah, well if I work a shift,then I can pay that too.
是的 我可以连那些一起还了
I can't work when I'm this sick!
我难受成这样根本不能工作
Ok, bye.
好的 再见
Fucking cunt!!
狗日的!
Candy.
凯蒂
- Candy. - Oh God!
- 凯蒂  - 哦 天哪
Answer!Answer, please!
接电话
He was just about to answer!
他正要接电话
- Give me the phone.- I want the fucking phone!
- 给我电话  - 我要用电话!
Don't fucking take it away from me!No! No!!
别拿我的电话 不行 不可以!
- We can do it. - No! Get away!! Nooooo!!
- 我们可以做到的   - 不 滚开! 不!!
Candy, you're bleeding.
凯蒂 你在流血
Why are you bleeding?
你怎么会流血?
The water has broken.Her cervix has dilated.
羊水破了 她的宫颈扩张了
This is what we didn't want to happen.
这是我们不愿意看到的
We call this an inevitable miscarriage.
我们都知道这是无法避免的流产
There's no going back.
我们尽力了
As I was explaining to Candy,she's going to have to go through a kind of... labour!
当我努力向凯蒂解释的时候 她正不得不经受...分娩的痛苦
I don't know however long that takes, you need to know that at this state of the pregnancy...
我不知道那持续了多久 你必须怀孕过才知道那个过程
...the baby is not going to survive.
孩子没能够活下来
I'm Sorry.
真对不起
Give me pethidine!
给我哌替啶(一种人工合成的镇痛和催眠药)
I want pethidine!
我需要哌替啶!
Will you give her the fucking pethidine, or what?
你不想给她哌替啶吗?
She's fucking in pain,can't you see this?
她实在是太痛苦了 难道你没看见?
That's it! Candy, push!
就这样! 凯蒂 用力!
Almost there! Push! That's it!!
快出来了 用力 对了! !
Can I hold it?
我可以抱抱吗?
Doctor, its leg moved.
医生 他的腿动了
It's just a spasm.
只是痉挛而已
It moved!
他明明动了!
Hell
地狱
- How much did you get?  - 50.
- 你赚了多少钱?  - 50块
That guy is still back there.
那家伙又来了
- Maybe you'll sell some. Yeah? - Alright.
- 也许你会卖一点 会吗?  - 好吧
Everything we ever did...
我们所做的一切
we did with the best of intentions...
都怀着美好的愿望
But.. events tumble!and the years pile up.
但是..年复一年 事与愿违!
The world is very bewildering to a junkie.
对一个瘾君子来说 世界是扑朔迷离的
Yeah, we're all good!
耶 我们都很棒
- Well... Tastes bad. - Fuck!
- 纯度不够  - 靠!
Here you go.
开始吧
Do you feel anything?
你察觉到什么了吗?
No.
没啊
- Shit!  - Shit!
- 妈的!  - 我靠!
and still... you cling to the concept of change.
你仍然坚持思想的转变
Hey, Schumann...
嘿 舒曼
...we are thinking of moving up the country for a while.
我们正打算搬到乡下住一阵
Give methadone a try.
试试美沙酮(一种镇痛药)
What the fuck difference would it make?
这东西有什么不同?
The air's cleaner, for one.
可以当空气清新剂
It's a kitchen.
这是厨房
It's a bit dark, isn't it?
有点暗 不是吗?
Yeah.
是的
Yeah, we Could um...
是的 我们可以..
knock out a hole...and put a skylight.
打一个洞..开个天窗
I love you.
我爱你
Any frozen peas?
有冷冻青豆吗?
No.
没
I got one! There he is!
我找到一个 在那儿
It was all the way down in the turbo frost.
一直是涡轮霜冻
I can not believe you didn't do this, this morning.
你早上竟然没有准备
What time are they coming?
他们啥时候到?
Fuck!!
靠!!
What's the date?
生产日期是多少?
Oh no, this expired a month ago.
哦 不 过期一个月了
Look at that! It smells bad!
你自己看 难闻死了!
- That's got that kind of chicken smell! - Yeah it does doesn't it!
- 整个厨房都臭了! - 难道不是吗?
Not to worry, we'll just baste it in lots of stuff! Like uh...
别担心 亲爱的 我们有很多东西可以用来调味
Basil, uh... honey? Bayleaves or something?
比如薄荷叶 月桂叶什么的?
What's in the cupboard?
橱柜里有什么?
What do you put on a roast?
你用什么烤肉呢?
How long did it take you to get out here?
你们到这儿花了多长时间?
Oh, About an hour and 40 minutes? Dear?
大概1小时40分钟? 亲爱的?
Yeah, about... 40? 45?
是的 大约40 还是45分钟?
Much traffic?
不堵车吗?
No, pretty good run really.
不会 一路畅通
Can't complain.
无可挑剔
It's so beautiful here,the drive down was so beautiful.
这儿太美了 开车是种享受
Yeah, it's... Countryside.
是啊 这是乡村
Had any news on the job front?
找工作有着落了吗?
Um... Well it's pretty... There's not much work around here.We're getting by on the dole.
额..还行吧..这儿的岗位不是很多 我们靠救济金还过得去
Well, apparently I might be able to get some work hay bailing.
那么 看来我要找份工作贴补家用了
Hay bailing?
贴补家用?
- Ooooh! Tough work, hay bailing!- Yeah.
- 哦! 辛苦工作 勉强糊口? - 是的
So! What can I do in the kitchen?
既然这样 我帮忙做饭吧
Nothing mum, really! It's fine!
不需要 真的 我能行!
Nonsense, there must be something I can do to help.
废话 一定有什么我能帮忙的
Everything's under control.
我自己就能搞定
The oven's heating up.
炉子烧开了
We're running a bit behind.
我们有些落伍了
No worries, mate.
别担心 伙计
Oh This is unbelievable.You go to all this trouble to invite us up here...
这真是难以置信 你煞费苦心就是为了请我们到这儿来
...and you can't even manage the simple decency of getting the meal together on time!
而且你竟然不能按时准备一餐便饭
Get off my case, mum!
别管我 妈
Is not food that's even the issue here.
食物还在其次
It's your attitude!
问题是你的态度
Okay, let's just calm down. Lunch will be ready in less than an hour.
好吧 我们都冷静 午饭不到一小时就好了
Who wants some wine?
谁想来点儿酒?
That chicken is rock solid!
那鸡肉像石头!
We're not going to be eating before midnight.
我们午夜前不打算吃东西
And where are the vegetables?
蔬菜在哪儿呢?
Hey hey, Let's all calm down, honey.
嘿 嘿 大家都静一静 亲爱的
What do you think is about?
你在想什么?
Sunday Lunch.It's a pretty simple thing.
周日午餐 本来很简单的一件事
But with you two, there's no such thing as simple.
但是你俩一掺和 就没简单的事
The drugs!
毒品!
The drugs always come first.
你们就知道吸毒!
Hey no, that is not true.
不 不是那样的
We're doing really well now.
我们现在已经做的很好了
Do you have any idea...
你知道什么
...what you have done to my family?
你对我的家庭都做过什么?
To me?
对我呢?
What happened to that beautiful girl?
那个美丽的女孩怎么啦?
What happened?
怎么了?
Can't you see?
难道你看不见?
Don't you understand?
难道你不明白?
I have been clutching my fucking fists since I was 6 years old.
我六岁起就攥紧了拳头
Look at my fucking fists! Look at them!
看看我的拳头 仔细看看
Look at them, you fucking bitch!
看看他们 你这烂货
Don't you understand?
难道你不明白
No! I gotta clench my hands!
我明白! 我会握紧我的手!
I gotta clench my hands! I can't relax.
我会握紧我的手不放松
Darling, darling! Look!It's been a big move.
亲爱的 亲爱的 快看! 这是个大动作!
It's been a big year.
这是不平凡的一年
There's been lots of changes.
有很多变化
C'mon, you've lost a child.
你们失去了一个孩子
But you ARE getting your lives together.I can see that!
但是你们的生命连在一起 我可以看到
Just go.
去吧
Fuck off.
滚!
Forget lunch.
忘记午餐的事吧
Can we?
可以吗?
Can we cancel the lunch?
可以取消午餐吗?
Maybe we can just make this another day.
我们可以另外挑个好日子
Today is just a bad day.I'm sorry.
今天不行 我很抱歉
I'm scared.
我好怕
There's nothing to be scared of.
没什么可怕的
D'you think we're going to end?
你觉得我们结束了吗?
- We'll never end. - It'll end.
- 我们永远不会结束  - 会的
It's not gonna work.
这不管用
Is that the flu vaccine?
是流感疫苗吗?
It's medicine.
是药
It's leading us not into temptation.
它指引我们免于诱惑
Hey Candy, check out this.
嘿 凯蒂 看看这个
Brickie's labourer.
招泥水工
- I'll give it a call, eh. - Why don't you do that.
- 我要打个电话  - 打吧
- Hi.- Hey!
- 嗨 - 嘿
This is Paul. He lives up the road.
这是保罗 他住在这条路的上方
Good day.
你好!
He's got some good home grow.
他有些家庭自制好东西
Great.Can I get some more?
太好了 我能多弄一些吗?
Um... There is none left.
嗯 已经没有了
Then I'll grab a beer.
那我要一杯啤酒
There's none of that either.
也没有了
I'm gonna go and get some more pot.
我要出去爽一下
Uh.. We gonna grab some dinner,or What?
呃..我们不吃晚餐了吗?
No, you eat! I'll be fine.
不 你吃! 我不用
You want some money? I got paid.
你需要钱吗? 我结工资了
- No. - No, it's okay mate.
- 不 -  没关系的 伙计
Where were you?
你们去哪儿了?
Don't you fuck this one with your negative comments.
难道你不打算说几句难听的吗?
What are you doing?
你在干嘛?
Going back to my art.
回到我的艺术之中
Does not mean anything to you?
难道这对你有什么意义吗?
Have you been fucking that guy?
你和那家伙上床了吗?
You do not know what you're talking about.
你在胡说八道
Where have you been all night?
你整个晚上都去哪儿了?
Away from you.
远离你
You fucked him, didn't you?
你跟他上床了 对不对?
Firstly...
首先...
...You do not know what you're talking about.
你在胡说八道
Secondly...
其次...
...I hate the sound of your voice.
我讨厌你的声音
Thirdly...
第三...
...Why don't you just fuck off?
你他妈给我滚蛋
I mean, really!
我是认真的
Fuck off!
滚你妈的蛋!
Wakey wakey.Hands off snakey!
醒醒 醒醒
What the fuck is that?
那该死的东西是啥
A statement of fact.What do you think it is?
如你所见 你认为是啥?
And what's this with your mother anyway?
关你妈什么事?
Well if it's not her...
如果不是她
...Then you.
那么你
Great.
很好
Okay...You.
好吧..你
You think you're so smart,but youre just fuckin' mad!
你自作聪明 其实是个疯子!
That's really good, Candy.
说得好 凯蒂
That's good, glad you think that.
说得好 很高兴你这么想
Your a fuckin' poet!
你是个混蛋诗人!
Once upon a time, there was a Candy and Dan...
曾经 有一对男女名叫丹和凯蒂
Things were very hot that year...
那年一切都很火热
All the wax was melting on the trees...
所有的蜡烛都在树上融化
He would crawl on balconies, climb everywhere. Do anything for her...
他在阳台上蠕动 到处攀爬 为她做任何事
My Danny boy.
我的丹尼男孩
Thousands of birds. Thetiniest birds adorned her hair...
成千上万的鸟儿 最小的鸟儿装点着她的秀发
Everything was golden...
一切都是金色的
One night the bed caught fire...
一天晚上 欲火点燃了绣床
He was handsome, and a very good criminal...
他风度翩翩 坏得恰到好处
We lived on sunlight and chocolate bars...
我们住在阳光和巧克力宫殿里
It was the afternoon of extravagant delight...
午后纵情狂欢
Danny, the Daredevil...
丹尼 铤而走险的战士
Candy the blessing...
凯蒂为你祈祷
The day's last rays of sunshine cruise like sharks....
那天的余晖鲨鱼般巡游
"I wanna try it your way this time!"
这次 我要试试你的办法
You came into my life really fast, and I liked it.
你如此迅速地进入我的生命 并且我喜欢
We squelched in the mud of our joy.
我们在欢愉的泥泞中碾得粉碎
I was wet thighed with the surrender...
我双腿潮湿 屈服于你
Then there was a gap in things...
万物之中有条鸿沟
And the whole earth tilted...
整个大地都倾斜了
This is the business.This is what we're after.
这就是我们追随的
With you inside me...Comes the night...
你在我体内 伴着夜晚降临
... never again sleep ...
难再入睡
... a monster in the pool ...
水池中的怪物
... Part of the black nature, to board ...
黑暗本质的一部分 飞翔
... chickens and runnerbeans ...
鸡和奔跑的青豆
... everywhere I looked ...
我所看到的地方
... sometimes I hate you ...
有时我恨你
... Friday ...
星期五
... I didn't mean that ...
那并非我所指
storm ... years ...... sometimes I hate you ...
暴风雨..年复一年..有时我恨你
... a box of flowers by the bed...
床边的一盆花
... I broke your head ...
我一时失手
... from the back of the bed ...
打破了你的头
... the baby died in the morning ...
孩子死于清晨
... I gave him a name ...
我给他起了个名字
... His name was Thomas ...
他的名字叫托马斯
...Poor little guy...
可怜的小家伙
... his heart poundslike a voodoo drum ...
他的心像魔法鼓般跳动
My name is Daniel, I'm an addict.I'm clean today, but not for much longer.
我的名字叫丹尼尔 我是个瘾君子 我今天很干净 但不会长久
Get out.
滚
I suppose I should do just that.
我想我应该那样做
I am in my house Casper.
我在卡斯珀家
Promise me you'll stop.
答应我你会停下来
Promise me you'll stop before me.
答应我你在我之前会停下
can I talk to Dan Cutter,Please? It's Jim Wyatt here.
我是吉姆怀亚特 可以找丹接电话吗?
Yeah Jim, it's me.
吉姆 是我
Hi! Candy's in the hospital.
嗨! 凯蒂住院了
What?
什么?
She's suffered a bit of a nervous breakdown.
她有点精神衰弱
It's funny where it all ends up  isn't it?
结局很有趣 是吗?
Candy.
凯蒂
You okay?
你没事儿吧?
I was so frightened.
我真被你吓到了
Sorry.
对不起
I didn't really understand what was happening.
我不知道都发生什么了
Candy?
凯蒂?
Everything's dead.
一切都死亡了
Everything's turning blue.
一切都变成蓝色的了
It's hard through all this you know.
这很难承受
I don't care how wrong you've been living about your years.
我不在乎你曾经怎样虚度
I care about my daughter.
我只在乎我的女儿
What?
什么?
Whatever you're capable of...whatever she needs...
不管你能做什么 不管她要什么
Come on, we'll take you home.
走吧 我们带你回家
Let him go.
让他走
And that was it...
就那样
That was all that was scattered to the winds...
一切都随风消散
Casper was gone...
卡斯珀消失了
Schumann was lost...
舒曼消失了
Candy was off getting better...
凯蒂没有好转
The coast...
海岸...
Rehab...
改过迁善
And I...Was...
而我...
I was just...
我只是...
The washer, Dan.
清洗者 丹
World Championship washer.
世界冠军级的清洗者
One day, you'll wash for Australia.
有一天 你会为澳大利亚清洗
The world was full of startling new concepts.
这个世界充满了奇思妙想
I couldn't think.I couldn't breathe.
我无法思考 无法呼吸
I was waiting for her to come back.
我在等她回来
Because she was everything.
因为她是我的一切
She was everything to me.
她是我的一切
Hey Dan, you have a visitor.
嘿 丹 有人找你
Visit.
有人找
Just Tell her I'm not here.
跟她说我不在
Are you crazy?
你疯了吗?
Tell her I knocked off.
告诉她我不在!
Your friend is right here, just come.
你的朋友来了 快出来吧
- G'day. - Hey!
- 你好 - 嘿!
I thought it was tomorrow.
我还以为你明天才来
I couldn't wait.
我等不急了
Is that okay?
还好吗
Yeah! No, it's good!
挺好的
It's just!You look so beautiful.
你真漂亮
It's all that country air.
乡下的空气养人
So I finish in an hour.
我一小时后收工
Dan.
丹
Dan. Hey!Hey!
丹 嘿 嘿!
Danny, Danny! Hey!
丹尼 丹尼! 嘿!
It's Okay.Hey!
没关系的 嘿!
Hey, It's Okay,I'm here now.
嘿 没关系的 我来了
There's no going back.
我们没有可能了
If you're given a reprieve...
如果你得以解脱
I think it is good to remember...
你为何不去想想
...just how thin it is.
想想那孩子有多瘦小